{
    "cards": [
        {
            "front": "Leadership",
            "back:": "Key Trait in cyber security.",
            "source": "responsible for developing policies and procedures, manage risk, develop controls, manage attack surefaces, routine patches and effective confgiuration management."
        },
        {
            "front": "Governace",
            "back": "term that is a foundational concept in proper planning and management is necessary for sucess.Their needs to be the needed time put into program design. In other words what term to the GRC teams refelct,when crafting their effective responses"
        },
        {
            "front": "Governace, risk, compliance or GRC",
            "back": "this teams job is to create and maintain organizational polices that set the employee expectations, the approach to cyber security, and direct the work of technical teams.",
            "source": "select appropriate technologies designed to address carefully analyzed probelems is critical.planing and management is key to avoiding the emotion driven 'quick fix'."
        },
        {
            "front": "Policy",
            "back": "procedures refer to as a roadmap, meaning they give clear guildance and clear direction.",
            "source": "These documents will be used to define the response action."
        },
        {
            "front": "Security Operation Center",
            "back": "Location Where security professional monitor and protect critacal information assets in an organization"
        },
        {
            "front": "Cyber service-level Objective or SLO",
            "back": "Standards that organization and their leadership must meet to ensure the security of their network",
            "source": "another tool to measure how well security operations protect the organizations assets."
        },
        {
            "front": "Risk Avoid",
            "back": "procatice of ceasing activity that present risk",
            "source": "Stop using a software application that has a high number of security vulnerabilities."
        },
        {
            "front": "Risk aceeptance",
            "back": "resonding by determining that a risk is within the organizations wiillingness to accept risk."
        },
        {
            "front": "Risk Mitigation",
            "back": "reponding by reducing risk to a level that is within the oganiztions willingness to accept risk."
        },
        {
            "front": "Risk transference",
            "back": "moving or sharing the responsibility of risk to another entity, such as by purchasing cyber security insureance."
        },
        {
            "front": "Threat Modeling",
            "back": "Process of identifying and assessing the possible threat actors and attack vectors that pose a risk to the security of an app, network, or other system.",
            "source": "identify the principal risk and tactics, techniques and procdures that a system might be put through for both the perspective of the attacker and defender. it is an accesment on the tools and positioing so that the opposition may react or perfrom certain actions. It is a deconstruction of parts to see the weakness of a system."
        },
        {
            "front": "MMTD",
            "back": "mean time to detect."
        },
        {
            "front": "MTTR",
            "back": "mean time to recover"
        },
        {
            "front": "ttp",
            "back": "Time to patch"
        },
        {
            "front": "Security Controls",
            "back": "Technical measures, such as firewalls, encryption, and employee training and awareness."
        },
        {
            "front": "Security Control Categories",
            "back": [
                {
                    "front": "Technical controls",
                    "back": "a security control categorie of hardware software and frimware."
                },
                {
                    "front": "Operation controls",
                    "back": "a Security Controls categorie that represents the people and the traiing they get."
                },
                {
                    "front": "Managerial Controls",
                    "back": "Type of security control that is the oversight of the informaion system or the risk identification tool."
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "front": "Preventative",
            "back": "a security control function type that happens before an attack.",
            "source": "security function like a firewall or antimalware."
        },
        {
            "front": "Detective",
            "back": "a security control function type that is related to recording of loggging during an attack",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "Corrective",
            "back": "a security control function that is mainly after an attack",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "responsive",
            "back": "the security control function that serves as the playbook after finding out an incedent has occured",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "compensating",
            "back": "this security control function serves as a substitute for a principle control, recommended as a security standard",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "Passive dicovery",
            "back": "Network capture, host discovery,finding channels, sniffing protocols is ",
            "source": "methods to identify systems , services, and protocols indirectly"
        },
        {
            "front": "Threat Actor",
            "back": "person or entity responsible for anevent that has been identified as a security risk or as an incident",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "Edge Discovery",
            "back": "composed of internet facing servers",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "penatration test",
            "back": "task is to expliot the envronment and evalulate the effectiveness of the exsisting protections",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "Security functional type",
            "back": [
                {
                    "front": "Asset Inventory",
                    "back": "a method that is Knowing all the hardware and software on site for a reduction of the attack surface.",
                    "source": ""
                },
                {
                    "front": "Access Control",
                    "back": "a method of reducing the attack sureface byusing multifactor authentication and withholding access tonon-authuratized users",
                    "source": ""
                },
                {
                    "front": "Patching and Updating",
                    "back": "A method of reducing the attack sureface by keeping things up to date of know vulnerabilities.",
                    "source": ""
                },
                {
                    "front": "Network Segmentaion",
                    "back": "A method of reducing the attack          surface by breaking the network into smaller subnets",
                    "source": ""
                },
                {
                    "front": "Removing Unnecessary Components",
                    "back": "if a system app or process is not needed what                 should be done to redurece the attack surface",
                    "source": ""
                }
            ],
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "Patch Management",
            "back": "Regularly monitoring, assessing, and updating a software like OS, application, and device drivers.",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "Patch Considerations",
            "back": [
                "who are the persons or people responsible for reviewing the            vendor supplied newletters and security patch docs",
                "mechanisms to  path OS and the apps running on it.",
                "patch management principles for cloud resources",
                "assigning updates into urgent, important, and non critical             categories.",
                "patch test env to see out important and urgent patches can be            install and analyzed before production deployment.",
                "Detailed logging to support monitoring and troubleshooting",
                "eval of frimware updates.",
                "immediate push of critical security updates",
                "routine schedule for the rollout of non critical patches."
            ],
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "Patch Testing",
            "back": "Determining if a patch is causing problems.",
            "source": "it is a mix of hardware and software and configuration settings. Testing is done on an isolated system to see if any problems are caused by the patch and if the patch did infact remove the bugs or vulerabilities that it was supposed to remove."
        },
        {
            "front": "Centralized Configuration Management system",
            "back": "Allows to define device config on the management serverthat can push settings to endpoints",
            "source": "For consistency across all systems and enforcement by over writing the changes."
        },
        {
            "front": "Reactive maintenance",
            "back": "The response of a problem or outage.",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "Proactive maintenance",
            "back": "To prevent future issues or safely proform work .",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "front": "",
            "back": "",
            "source": ""
        }
    ]
}
